SHRATHINTH VENKATESH

 $shrathinth.com \diamond (262) \cdot 421 \cdot 5281 \diamond shrathinth13@hotmail.com$

SUMMARY

Economist/Applied micro-econometrician with a track record of consistently and creatively solving a diverse set of problems. Experienced with analysing survey data and medical claims data from public and private insurance providers. Implemented a wide variety of empirical strategies to examine changes in labour market outcomes, health outcomes and their effects. Drawn robust conclusions from limited data and indirect treatment observation.

EDUCATION

University of Wisconsin - Milwaukee

2021

PhD in Economics

Focus: Labor Economics, Economics of Education, Health Economics

PES Institute of Technology, India

2013

BE in Mechanical Engineering Focus: Material Science

EXPERIENCE

Graduate Research Assistant

August 2017 - December 2019

College of Nursing, Department of Economics

University of Wisconsin - Milwaukee

- · Assessed the impact of the PERISCOPE perinatal health intervention using claims data from Medicaid and private insurance providers in Wisconsin.
- · Used propensity score matching and difference-in-differences regressions to find a 20% increase in prescription use and a \$310 reduction in emergency costs.
- · Used machine learning techniques including random forest, decision tree and K-nearest neighbours in R for variable selection and testing.
- · Reported the results of our study in non-technical language.
- · Communicated and worked with health professionals to create appropriate empirical models.

Lecturer

September 2020 - May 2021

Department of Economics

University of Wisconsin - Whitewater

- · Taught basic principles of statistics and statistical analysis using Excel.
- · Created content to engage students and allow easy understanding of complex statistics concepts.

Graduate Teaching Assistant

August 2014 - May 2020

Department of Economics

University of Wisconsin - Milwaukee

- · Taught a diverse set of students with a wide range of technical backgrounds.
- · Clearly communicated statistics and econometric theory, with the express purpose of applying it to analyze real data.
- · Taught data analysis using R and STATA to undergraduate and graduate students with little prior knowledge.
- · Designed the syllabus and structure of four different courses over 8 semesters.

TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

Skills Applied econometrics, Machine learning, Data Analysis
Tools Proficient STATA, R, Matlab, LATEX

Python, SQL, SAS, SPSS, E-Views, JAVA, C++

RESEARCH

,	theoming at Education Economics)
"The Returns to Drinking: Social Workers or Social Jobs?" with SJ	Adams, JS Heywood & D Ullman
Under Review	
"Are the Returns to Education Still Rising?"	Working Paper
"Changes in the Returns to Education: Evidence from Three Cohorts	of the NLSY" Working Paper
"A Methodological Approach for Evaluating Economic Effects of Perina	ntal Psychiatric Provider Consulta-
tion" with SJ Adams, JJ Doering CL Wichman, S Kuehn & A Laszews	ski In Progress
"Changes in education's effect on job sorting"	In Progress

PRESENTATIONS AND HONORS

Familiar

Midwest Economic Association Annual Meeting, St.Louis, MO	2019
Wisconsin Economics Association Annual Meeting, Stevens Point, WI	2019
University of Wisconsin - Milwaukee Economics Labor Lunch	2019
University of Wisconsin - Milwaukee Applied Microeconomics group	2019
Richard Perlman Prize for Outstanding Paper in Labor Economics	2018
University of Wisconsin - Milwaukee Chancellors Graduate student award	2014 & 2015

PROFESSIONAL SERVICE

Midwest Economic Association Annual Meeting, St. Louis, MO	Discussant	2019
Graduate Student Applied Microeconomics Group, UWM	Co-organizer	2019

PROFESSIONAL ASSOCIATIONS

American Economic Association Midwest Economic Association

REFERENCES

Provided upon request.